Guide to the Victor Remer Historical Archives of the Children's Aid Society 1836-2006 (bulk 1853-1947) MS 111
New-York Historical Society
- Series XIII - Photographs, 1890-circa 1960
  - Subseries XIII.2 - Photographs of City Facilities, Programs and Services, and Special Events, circa 1904- circa 1955; 1908-1945
    - Sub-Subseries XIII.2.A - Photographs of Industrial Schools, Lodging Houses, and Children's Clubs
      - Newsboys and/or unidentified Lodging House - 4 prints by unknown photographers, and a page with 6 2x5x2.5 prints glued on, by unknown photographer, undated (Offsite-box 976, Folder 10)
      - Newsboys Lodging House - photomechanical reproductions, undated (Offsite-box 976, Folder 11)
      - Rhinelander Industrial School (for crippled children) - naps, sewing, jewelry making, dressmaking, apple week party, exterior - 4 prints by Underwood & Underwood numbered 120837-839 and 138632 (1911), 2 prints by A. Tennyson Beals (54397-98), 2 prints by Brown & Dawson (12787 and unknown), 1 print by Hiram Myers (1923) and 2 prints by unknown photographer, circa 1911, 1915, 1923 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 12)
      - Sixth Street Industrial School - cooking, dining hall, savings bank, exterior - 7 prints by unknown photographers, 1926, circa 1947-1954, undated (Offsite-box 976, Folder 13)
      - Sullivan Street Industrial School - exercising in yard, dancing, carpentry, cooking, classroom, games - 5 8x10 prints by Brown & Dawson/Publishers Photo Service nubmered 24993-25031, 2 8x10 prints by unknown photographer, circa 1913-1924 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 14)
      - Sullivan Street Industrial School - playground, demolition, carpentry, reading - 9 8x10s by Paul Parker, circa 1926-1932 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 15)
      - Lower West Side Center (Sullivan St.) - Boys Woodworking, Girls' Sewing Club - 5 8x10 and 7x10 prints by unidentified photographers, 2 5x7 prints (lunchroom, Thanksgiving play) also by unknown photographers (Offsite-box 976, Folder 16)
      - Utopia Children's House - 3 8x10 prints, 3 7x9 prints (incl. 1 duplicate) by Richard Ward and unknown photographers, circa 1930 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 17)
      - West Side Industrial School (419 W. 38th St.) - Christmas, folk dancing, girls with dolls, boys in gym - 16 5x8.25 prints by Underwood & Underwood, numbered 119164-183 and no number, circa 1910-1915 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 18)
      - West Side Industrial School (419 W. 38th St.) - sewing, cooking - 2 8x10 prints by Brown & Dawson and 1 cropped print, numbered 3235, 3243, circa 1913-1920 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 19)
      - West Side Industrial School (419 W. 38th St.) - forge class, Thanksgiving - 2 vintage 8x10s by A. Tennyson Beals (ca. 1915) and 1 8x10 reprint by unknown photographer (Offsite-box 976, Folder 20)
      - West Side School (renamed West Side Children's Center in 1930) (419 W. 38th St.) - carpentry, folk dance, library - 3 8x10 prints by Paul Parker, 1 8x10 by Paul J. Woolf, 1 6.5x8.5 by Schoenhals, 1 5x7, circa 1928-1929, 1940s (Offsite-box 976, Folder 21)
      - West Side School (renamed West Side Children's Center in 1930) - schermerhorn Playground - 14 prints by Paul Parker, A. Tennyson Beals, others, circa 1928-1932, undated (Offsite-box 976, Folder 22)
      - West Side School (renamed West Side Children's Center in 1930) - roof - 6 3.5x5.75 prints by Miss Patten, undated (Offsite-box 976, Folder 23)
      - West Side Children's Center - Photo album documenting interior and exterior spaces, circa 1955 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 24)
    - Sub-Subseries XIII.2.B - Photographs of Unidentifed CAS City Facilities
      This subseries consists of 11 folders of mostly vintage photographic prints of mixed unidentified Children's Aid Society city facilities, arranged alphabetically by subject matter, followed by 3 folders of miscellaneous unidentified facilities, and 1 folder of miscellaneous facilities. Possible identifications for some facilities are suggested.
      - Apple Week at unidentified facilities [Rhinelander, Newsboys] - 3 8x10 prints by A. Tennyson Beals (32737-43), 1 8x10 print by Hiram Myers, 1 5x7 by unknown photographer, circa 1920s (Offsite-box 976, Folder 25)
      - Christmas at [53rd Street School] 1927 and [Lower West Side Center] 1931 - 3 8x10s by Steffen (1927) and Paul Parker (1931), 1927, 1931 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 26)
      - Cobbling Classes at unidentified industrial schools [West Side School and East River School] - 1 6x8 print by Underwood & Underwood (122200), 1 8x10 by Publishers Photo Service (24435), 2 8x10s and 2 5x7s `by unknown photographers, circa 1908-1930 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 27)
      - Cooking Classes at unidentified facilities - 2 8x10 prints by A. Tennyson Beals, 1 8x10 by Paul Parker, 1 5x7 by unknown photographer, circa 1915-1932 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 28)
      - Crippled Children - Horse-drawn wagonette (ca. 1913) and bus (began operating 1916) for crippled children. [Henrietta, Rhinelander, and Avenue B Schools all served crippled children - these children are probably going to Rhinelander] - 1 print by Brown & Dawson, 1 print, duplicate, and reprint by A. Tennyson Beals, circa 1913 and 1916 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 29)
      - Dining halls at unidentified schools - 4 8x10 prints by Brown & Dawson (incl. 1 duplicate), 2 8x10 prints by A. Tennyson Beals, 1 8x10 print by Hiram Myers, 1 8x10 by unknown photographer, circa 1913-1927 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 30)
      - Gymnasiums with young men (3 prints include basketball) at unidentified facilities - 2 prints by Underwood & Underwood, 2 prints by unknown photographer, circa 1908-1920s (Offsite-box 976, Folder 31)
      - Nursery class at unidentified facility [Sullivan Street, Avenue B, Italian, Jones?] - 3 8x10 prints by Brown & Dawson 21792-21794, circa 1913-1924 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 32)
      - Nursery or kindergarten classes at unidentified facilities - 2 8x10s by Brown & Dawson (3229 and 25012), 1 8x10 by Hiram Myers (52539), circa 1915-1932 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 33)
      - Playgrounds at unidentified facilities - 1 8x10 by A. Tennyson Beals, 2 8x10s by Paul Parker, circa 1915-1932 (Offsite-box 976, Folder 34)
      - Sewing classes at unidentified facilities - 4 8x10 prints by unidentified photographers, undated (Offsite-box 976, Folder 35)
      - Unidentified Children's Center [Utopia, Henrietta/Columbus Hill, or Harlem] - 5 8x10s (incl. 1 duplicate) by Publisher's Photo Service numbered 24694-24698, circa 1920-1924 (Offsite-box 977, Folder 1)
      - Unidentified boys' lodging house or school - exterior winter bonfire - 1 6x8.5 print by Underwood & Underwood, circa 1908-1913 (Offsite-box 977, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous unidentified industrial schools, lodging houses, or children's centers [Italian school among others?] - sign painting, mural painting, classrooms, group portrait, field trip Central Park toy boats - 2 prints by Underwood & Underwood, 2 prints by A. Tennyson Beals, 1 print [by Brown & Dawson], 1 print by Daily Mirror, circa 1908-1926 (Offsite-box 977, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous Industrial School and Lodging House Building Exteriors - 4 8x10 reprints copied from Annual Reports, photographers unknown, undated (Offsite-box 977, Folder 4)
    - Sub-Subseries XIII.2.C - Photographs of CAS Programs, Services, and Special Events
      XIII.2.C contains 6 folders of photographs of CAS services (dental, medical, etc.), arranged alphabetically by service, followed by 2 folders of special events.
      - Dental Services - 11 prints (incl. 1 duplicate and 1 cropped) by Underwood & Underwood, Publishers' Photo Service, A. Tennyson Beals, Hiram Myers, and unknown photographer, circa 1911-1938 and undated (Offsite-box 977, Folder 5)
      - Excursion Program - 1 reprint of Rockefeller Excursion by unknown photographer, circa 1928 (Offsite-box 977, Folder 6)
      - Housekeeper Service - 2 prints by unknown photographers, 1933, undated (Offsite-box 977, Folder 7)
      - Housekeeper Service or Service Bureau for Negro Children or Foster Home Department - 2 8x10s by Paul Parker, undated (Offsite-box 977, Folder 8)
      - Medical Services (milk program, clinics, etc.) - Includes photographs from Italian School, West Side School, and unidentified facilities - 11 prints by A. Tennyson Beals, Brown & Dawson, Publishers Photo Service, Hiram Myers, unidentified photographers, circa 1913-1930s (Offsite-box 977, Folder 9)
      - Nutrition Program - 4 8x10 portraits of children eating, by Paul Parker, circa 1929 (Offsite-box 977, Folder 10)
      - Duchess of Windsor visits CAS Medical/Dental Facility- 2 6.5x5.5 prints (NY Herald Tribune), undated (Offsite-box 977, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous special event publicity photographs - 3 8x10 prints by Paul Parker, undated (Offsite-box 977, Folder 12)
  - Subseries XIII.3 - Photographs of Country Facilties, circa 1908-1945
    This subseries consists of 4 boxes of photographs and disbound photo albums, and 2 bound photo albums, divided into 4 sub-subseries.
    XIII.3.A - Lewis Hine Prints of CAS Country Facilities - consists of prints by Lewis Hine of CAS country facilities, taken in 1928, arranged by print number. The photographs include a nearly complete set of 5x7 proofs numbered 1-84. Three numbers (45, 67, 79) are not represented, three additional numbers (5A, 31A, and 71A) are included, and there are a few duplicate proofs as well. The sub-subseries also includes 8x10 prints of many of these images. The images include many unpopulated landscapes, as well as images with people (especially farm school boys). The photographs were taken at a transitional time for the CAS, as the newly acquired Bowdoin Farm property in New Hamburg N.Y. was about to become a camp and farm school, replacing the Brace Farm School.
    XIII.3.B - Photographs of Farm Schools - contains photographs of the CAS farm training programs arranged chronologically with Brace Farm School first, followed by Bowdoin Farm School, and then unidentified Brace and/or Bowdoin Farm School. Within these divisions, folders are further subdivided by photographer, and arranged numerically by photograph number within the folders. The sub-subseries concludes with a set of 8 small format disbound photo albums entitled "Bowdoin Farm Boys" from 1935-1943, consisting of 549 2.75 x 4.5 portraits of young men who attended the farm school.
    XIII.3.C - Photographs of Camps - contains photographs of camp facilities, arranged alphabetically, and further subdivided chronologically. The Bowdoin Camp photographs include a bound photo album.
    XIII.3.D - Photographs of Convalescent Facilities - contains photographs of CAS convalescent facilities, arranged alphabetically by facility.
    Researchers should note that two of the same facilities used for camps were also used for farm schools, and Goodhue camp was also used as a home for girls preparing to go to foster care. Thus, there is some overlap between the sub-subseries. Lewis Hines' photographs of mixed country facilities are arranged as sub-subseries A. Photographs of Goodhue Home are arranged with Goodhue Camp in sub-subseries C. For a partial history of facility name and location changes, please see the note for Series IX.2: Facilities-Alphabetical. For a history of convalescent facilities, please see the note for Series X.
    - Sub-Subseries XIII.3.A - Lewis Hine Prints of CAS Country Facilities
      Sub-subseries XIII.3.A consists of prints by Lewis Hine of CAS country facilities, taken in 1928, arranged by print number. The photographs include a nearly complete set of 5x7 proofs numbered 1-84. Three numbers (45, 67, 79) are not represented, three additional numbers (5A, 31A, and 71A) are included, and there are a few duplicate proofs as well. The sub-subseries also includes 8x10 prints of many of these images. The images include many unpopulated landscapes, as well as images with people (especially farm school boys). The photographs were taken at a transitional time for the CAS, as the newly acquired Bowdoin Farm property in New Hamburg N.Y. was about to become a camp and farm school, replacing the Brace Farm School.
      - Country Facilities - 43 5x7 proofs by Lewis Hine numbered 1-39, 1928 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 1)
      - Country Facilities - 19 8x10 prints by Lewis Hine corresponding to selected proofs numbered 1-39, 1928 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 2)
      - Country Property Landscapes - 30 5x7 proofs by Lewis Hine numbered 40-70, 1928 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 3)
      - Bowdoin Farm Property Landscapes - 8 8x10 prints by Lewis Hine corresponding to selected proofs numbered 41-50, 1928 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 4)
      - Brace Farm - Farm School and Camp - 15 5x7 proofs by Lewis Hine numbered 71-84, 1928 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 5)
    - Sub-Subseries XIII.3.B - Photographs of Farm Schools
      Brace Farm School, in Valhalla N.Y., operated 1894-1928 with the goal of exposing boys and young men to farm work, to ease the transition to farm life they would experience after subsequent placement by the Emigration/Placing-Out Program. Bowdoin Farm School, in New Hamburg N.Y., began operating in 1929 and provided a more extensive farm training program to prepare young men for employment on farms.
      This sub-subseries contains photographs of the CAS farm schools arranged chronologically with Brace Farm School first, followed by Bowdoin Farm School, and then unidentified Brace and/or Bowdoin Farm School. Within these divisions, folders are further subdivided by photographer, and arranged numerically by photograph number within the folders. The sub-subseries concludes with a set of 8 small format disbound photo albums entitled "Bowdoin Farm Boys" from 1935-1943, consisting of 549 2.75 x 4.5 portraits of young men who attended the farm school.
      - Brace Farm School - 5 6x8 prints and 1 8x10 print by Underwood & Underwood, circa 1908-1913 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 6)
      - Brace Farm School - 2 hand-tinted postcards and 1 mounted print by unknown photographers, circa 1911-1920 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 7)
      - Brace Farm School - 11 8x10 prints by Paul Parker (incl. 1 duplicate), circa 1927 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 8)
      - Bowdoin property landscapes by unknown photographer - 2 4.5x6.75 prints on paper by unknown photographer, circa 1928 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 9)
      - Bowdoin Farm School - 1 2.5x3.5 print of FDR's visit, 1933 August 10 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 10)
      - Bowdoin Farm School - 7 8x10 prints of first Bowdoin Farm Boys' Fair by Stenson & Van Vlack, 1935 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 11)
      - Bowdoin Farm School - 2 prints by unknown photographers: "Graduation Class 1939" and "Mixing a Little Fun with Their Daily Chores", 1939, 1940 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 12)
      - Bowdoin Farm School - 21 small prints - stills from film "Follow the Plough", 1942 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 13)
      - Bowdoin Farm School- 8x10 prints by John Rogers (16, numbered 1-16, missing #12, includes 15 A and B), 1 composite collage of small prints including these same images, circa 1942-1945 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 14)
      - Bowdoin Farm School - 28 2.5x4.5 prints, 3 negatives, and 1 small piece of film negative with note, all from enclosed envelope labelled "Mr. Lane - 12/43 Willard Pictures", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 15)
      - Bowdoin Farm School - 1 8x10 by H. Armstrong Roberts, undated (Offsite-box 978, Folder 16)
      - Bowdoin Farm School - 4 8x10 prints (incl. 1 duplicate) and 1 6.5x8.5 print by unknown photographers, undated (Offsite-box 978, Folder 17)
      - Bowdoin Farm School and Camp - 8 prints from a series numbered 2, 3, 6, 12, 21, 22, 35, 36 - unknown photographer, undated (Offsite-box 978, Folder 18)
      - Brace and/or Bowdoin Farm School - 9 8x10 prints by Paul Parker, circa 1927-1932 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 19)
      - Brace and/or Bowdoin Farm School - photographs used in annual reports by Hiram Myers and unknown photographers (2 8x10s, 1 4.5x6.5, 1 3.5x4.5, 1 6.5x8.5), circa 1925, 1926, 1933, 1934 (Offsite-box 978, Folder 20)
      - Brace and/or Bowdoin Farm - 4 8x10 exteriors of facilities by unknown photographers, undated (Offsite-box 978, Folder 21)
      - Brace and/or Bowdoin Farm School - 4 8x10s, 1 3.5x4.5, 1 3.5x5.5 by unknown photographers, undated (Offsite-box 978, Folder 22)
      - Bowdoin Farm Boys - 76 2.75 x 4.5 prints removed from "Bowdoin Farm Boys 1935 I", 1935 March 8-1935 May 29 (Offsite-box 979, Folder 1)
      - Bowdoin Farm Boys - 79 2.75 x 4.5 prints and 1 negative removed from "Bowdoin Farm Boys 1935 II" (Offsite-box 979, Folder 2)
      - Bowdoin Farm Boys - 58 2.75 x 4.5 prints removed from "Farm Boys 1937" (Offsite-box 979, Folder 3)
      - Bowdoin Farm Boys - 71 2.5 x 4.75 prints removed from "Farm Boys 1938" (Offsite-box 979, Folder 4)
      - Bowdoin Farm Boys - 100 2.5 x 4.75 prints removed from "Farm Boys 1939 I" (Offsite-box 979, Folder 5)
      - Bowdoin Farm Boys - 65 2.5 x 4.75 prints removed from "Bowdoin Farm 1940" (Offsite-box 979, Folder 6)
      - Bowdoin Farm Boys - 63 2.5 x 4.75 prints removed from "Farm Boys 1941" (Offsite-box 979, Folder 7)
      - Bowdoin Farm Boys - 37 2.5 x 4.75 prints removed from "Bowdoin Farm 1942" (Offsite-box 979, Folder 8)
      - Bowdoin Farm School Boy Photo Albums - original housing, 1935-1943 (Offsite-box 980)
    - Sub-Subseries XIII.3.C - Photographs of Camps
      Subseries XIII.3.C contains photographs of CAS camp facilities and activities, arranged alphabetically by facility, and then chronologically for each facility. The Bowdoin Camp photographs include a bound photo album. Miscellaneous photographs are at the end of the sub-subseries. Goodhue camp also served as a home for girls preparing to be sent to foster care. Some images of Goodhue in that function are interfiled with the Goodhue camp images, and noted on the folder. CAS camps shared facilities with CAS farm schools, so researchers should be aware that a few images of camp facilities may also be found in sub-subseries XIII.3.A and B.
      - Photo Album - "Boys' Summer Camp at Temple and Helen P. Bowdoin Memorial Farm" includes 8x10s by Paul Parker and others, and captions, 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 1247, Box 981)
      - Bowdoin Boys' Camp - 11 8x10 prints by Paul Parker, 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 1)
      - Bowdoin Boys' Camp - 14 8x10 prints by Paul Parker, 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 2)
      - Bowdoin Boys' Camp - Exteriors of facilities - 9 8x10 prints, 1 5x7, 4 3x5s, by Paul Parker and others, circa 1930 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 3)
      - Bowdoin Boys' Camp - 2 3x5.25 group shots of campers, 1940 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 4)
      - Bowdoin/Vanderbilt Boys' and Girls' Camps - 4 3x5 prints by unknown photographers, winter and summer, circa 1929, undated (Offsite-box 982, Folder 5)
      - Bowdoin/Vanderbilt Girls' Camp - 7 8x10 prints by Paul Parker, circa 1930 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 6)
      - Bowdoin/Vanderbilt Girls' Camp - Exteriors of facilities - 2 8x10 prints by Paul Parker, circa 1930 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 7)
      - Boys' Camp in Denville New Jersey - 4 6x8 prints by Underwood & Underwood, circa 1911 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 8)
      - [Brace Farm Camp, Valhalla NY] - 2 8x10 prints by A. Tennyson Beals, circa 1915-1927 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 9)
      - Brace Farm Camp, Valhalla - 1 8x10 reprint of a vintage print by unknown photographer, circa 1915-1927 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 10)
      - Brace Memorial Newsboys' Summer Camp (Southfield Camp) - 1 mounted 6.5x8.5 print, photographer unknown, 1922 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 11)
      - Goodhue Camp, Staten Island - 7 8x10 prints and 1 5x7 proof by Brown & Dawson and/or Publishers' Photo Service, circa 1912, 1918, undated (Offsite-box 982, Folder 12)
      - Goodhue Camp - 10 8x10 prints, 1 6.5x10, and 1 5.5x7.25, by unknown photographers, circa 1912, 1927, undated (Offsite-box 982, Folder 13)
      - Goodhue Camp - 1 8x10 print by A. Tennyson Beals, circa 1915-1927 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 14)
      - [Goodhue Camp] - 2 8x10 and 2 2.75x4.5 prints by unknown photographers, 1918, undated (Offsite-box 982, Folder 15)
      - Goodhue Camp/Goodhue Home - 17 small prints by unknown photographers, and photomechanical reproduction clipped from annual report, 1923, 1925, undated (Offsite-box 982, Folder 16)
      - Goodhue Camp - 14 8x10 prints by Paul Parker, incl. 1 duplicate, circa 1927-1930 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 17)
      - Kips' Bay Boys' Camp - 4 8x10 prints by Paul Parker and unknown photographer, circa 1927-1930, 1941 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 18)
      - Walkill Camp, New Paltz - 2 8x10 prints by unknown photographers, undated, post-1936 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 19)
      - Miscellaneous camp postcards, undated (Offsite-box 982, Folder 20)
      - Miscellaneous camp photographs by unknown photographers, undated (Offsite-box 982, Folder 21)
    - Sub-Subseries XIII.3.D - Photographs of Convalescent Facilities
      XIII.3.D contains photographs of CAS convalescent facilities and activities, arranged alphabetically by facility, and then chronologically for each facility. Folder 23 includes 5x7 photographs by Lewis Hine of both the Elizabeth Milbank Anderson and Milbank Convalescent Homes, arranged under the former. Some photographs of the Summer Home at Bath Beach Long Island are mixed with the Health Home at Coney Island, and noted on the folders. For a history of CAS convalescent facilities, please see the note for Series X.
      - Elizabeth Milbank Anderson Convalescent Home - 1 vintage and 2 reprint 8x10s by Underwood & Underwood, circa 1909-1913 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 22)
      - Elizabeth Milbank Anderson and Milbank Convalescent Homes - 27 5x7 proofs of photographs by Lewis Hine numbered 85-112. See also Folder 32., 1928 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 23)
      - Elizabeth Milbank Anderson Convalescent Home - 1 vintage 5x7 by unknown photographer [Lewis Hine?], 1 5x7 reprint, 1 8x10 reprint, circa 1928 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 24)
      - Elizabeth Milbank Anderson Home - 4 5x7 prints sent by a former client, circa 1940 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 25)
      - Grinnell Home for Convalescent Boys - 4 8x10 prints by Paul Parker (incl. 1 duplicate), circa 1929 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 26)
      - Health Home at Coney Island and Summer Home at Bath Beach - 7 vintage 6x8 prints and 1 8x10 reprint (original missing) by Underwood & Underwood, circa 1911 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 27)
      - Health Home at Coney Island - Babies' Ward - 2 6.5x8.5 prints by Underwood & Underwood, circa 1917 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 28)
      - Health Home at Coney Island and Summer Home at Bath Beach - 3 prints by unknown photographers 1 2.5x4.25 (torn), 1 5x7 (mounted), 1 8x10, and Health Home illustration used as frontispiece in annual reports, circa 1917, undated (Offsite-box 982, Folder 29)
      - [Martha Convalescent Home] - 7 3.5x4.5 prints with captions on back, undated (Offsite-box 982, Folder 30)
      - Milbank Convalescent Home - 3 8x10 prints by Paul Parker, circa 1926-1932 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 31)
      - Milbank Convalescent Home - 8 8x10 prints by Lewis Hine corresponding to proofs 101, 102, 105, 106, 107, 109 (2), and 110 - see also folder 23, 1928 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 32)
      - Milbank Convalescent Home - 2 8x10 prints, 1 5x7 print, 1 4x6 print by unknown photographers, circa 1930s (Offsite-box 982, Folder 33)
      - Summer Home at Bath Beach - 3 8x10 prints by Paul Parker, circa 1926-1932 (Offsite-box 982, Folder 34)
  - Subseries XIII.4 - Children, Streets, and Tenements